Elijah Raffo

Portland, OR 97224

(971) 275-7057 eliraffo@gmail.com <u>linkedin.com/in/eliraffo</u> eliraffo.github.io

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Project manager and data analyst with 2+ years of experience delivering business results within a fast-paced environment. Demonstrated experience leading a cross-function team focused on innovation, deriving actionable insights with data, and modelling complex business operations.

EDUCATION

Graduate Certificate in Business Intelligence and Analytics ● Portland State University

Oct. 2019 – June 2020

Concepts: Data Visualization ● Prescriptive Analytics (Linear Optimization, OCCAM) ● Data Mining & Machine Learning

GPA: 3.94 / 4.0

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration • University of Oregon

Sep. 2015 – June 2019

Major Concentration ● Operations and Business Analytics

GPA: 3.60 / 4.0

Minor • Computer Information Technology

Concepts: Database Management ● Predictive Analytics ● Descriptive Analytics ● Demand Forecasting ● Business Strategy

WORK EXPERIENCE

Program Manager and Data Analyst

Lam Research Corporation ● Portland, OR

Sep. 2019 - Current

<u>Managed</u> development programs for new deposition reactors which over 1-year fought for new market share in the logic and memory space by hitting aggressive vision targets and customer timelines:

- Coordinated a cross-functional team to identify and achieve ≥25% BOM cost reduction on a multi-million dollar system.
- Led multiple programs and projects through the development process to meet timeline requirements (alpha, beta, and unrestricted release).
- Drove cross-functional teams to highlight program/project risks and implement mitigations.

Assessed the validity of manufacturing (ACU) charges, and over 9-months generated a reduction of ≥\$1M in charges to the PECVD product group.

Demonstrated quantitatively the connection between manufacturing efficiency and the implementation of POA BOM structuring.

Operations Analyst

Lane Forest Products, Inc. ● Eugene, OR

June 2018 - June 2019

Quantified the efficiency of the Delivery Department by developing and applying a cost model within 3-months. Implemented a delivery pricing structure which identified and stopped losses on and increased profit on delivery by an estimated \$36,000 per year.

- Utilized visualization to explain the profit margin of all order combinations (~50,000 combinations) to stakeholders.
- Created and instituted a spreadsheet which uses a Google Distance API to automate and optimize the delivery price quoted to customers.

<u>Automated</u> a logistic reload which over 6-months moved 55,000 tons of material, resulting in becoming the customer's primary service provider. Managed the export of international orders by developing process mapping, managing documentation, and coordinating the flow of materials.

Supply Logistics Intern

Townshend's Tea Company ● Portland, OR

June 2017 - Sep. 2017

Redesigned the company's Point-of-Sale interface for all Eugene Teahouse locations which:

Improved storefront efficiency and created data which could depict customer preferences, inventory levels, and automate reorder points.

Years of Experience:

HIGHLIGHTED SKILLS

1 to 2 Years Python (Pandas, NumPy) ● R (ggplot, lessR) ● JavaScript (RESTful API's, Node.js, React.js) ● SAP

2 to 4 Years MS Excel (Power Pivot, Dashboards, Macros) ● Business Intelligence (Tableau, Power BI, DAX) ● SQL (Access, MySQL) ●

Linear Optimization (ompR, Solver) • MS Office (Projects, Visio, OneNote, Outlook, PowerPoint, Word)

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Lane Forest - Delivery Analysis	Townshend's - POS Redesign	Linear Optimization in R	Dataquest Portfolio
Operational analysis delivering impact	Automating operations, and creating a	Modelling business scenarios, and	Applying Data Science BKMs
with visualization	valuable data pipeline	creating actionable insights	to practical problems

Certified Associate in Project Management (PMI) ● Lean Six Sigma Green Belt (SSGI) ● Certificate of Outdoor Leadership (OPP)

http://eliraffo.github.io/ ● All projects and certifications can be viewed on GitHub